coastal.com 2016-10-19

# 

Essilor Group Canada Inc. ("Coastal", "we", "us", "our") respects your privacy and will at all times seek to comply with privacy laws. This privacy policy covers the site [www.coastal.com](http://www.coastal.com/). The personal information we collect about our users shall be carefully and adequately processed, and will not be disclosed, rented or sold to third parties other than described within this privacy policy.

We collect information to be able to process your order and to offer you our newsletter and special deals when it is time to refill your order (this will include your name, date of birth, e-mail, postal addresses, credit card information and details of any prescription supplied to you by your optician or medical practitioner). You will need to give your consent before any processing takes place and your personal data will only be used for the purposes stated in these terms and conditions and or at the point of collection. We are committed to maintaining the highest standards of personal data protection and will not collect information about you without your consent. 

When you apply for a job we encourage you to create a career account. The information we will collect is name, email address, referral source, address, and a resume that you may either upload to the site or import from linkedin. We use this information to determine whether or not you are eligible for the position in which you have applied and so that we may contact you to set up an interview. 

If you wish to refill your last order we will collect your email address and postal code and use the personal information and prescription information you have on file with in order to fulfill your request. 

We allow you to upload a photo of yourself so that you are able to try glasses or contacts on your photo to see what they would look like on you before ordering. If you wish to remove your photos from the site, you may do so by logging into your account and deleting it or by emailing us at the email address provided below.

If you choose to use our referral service to invite a friend to our site or provide us referrals for job openings, we will ask for your friend's name and email address. We will automatically send your friend a one-time email inviting him or her to visit the site. We store this information for the sole purpose of sending this one-time email and tracking the success of our referral program.

Or, if you provide your doctor's information, we will ask for your doctor's name and phone number, fax number (optional). We will use and store this information for the sole purpose of verifying your prescription.

Your friend or doctor may contact us at [privacy@coastal.com](mailto:privacy@coastal.com) to request that we remove this information from our database.

If you request information from us on the Investors page we will ask for your name, email address and phone number. We use this information in order to provide you with the information you have requested. 

Our Web site includes Social Media Features, such as the Facebook Like button [and Widgets, such as the Share this button or interactive mini-programs that run on our site]. These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it. 

You can import contacts from your Outlook or other email account address book to invite them to become members of our site. We collect the username and password for the email account you wish to import your contacts from and will only use it for that purpose.

Some pages may have the look and feel of being on [www.coastal.com](http://www.coastal.com/), however the information collected on these pages is not covered under this privacy policy. All information collected on the other domain is owned and controlled by a separate privacy policy.

This site contains links to other sites that are not owned or controlled by us. Please be aware that we are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage you to be aware when you leave our site and read the privacy policy of each and every site that collects personal information. This privacy policy applies only to information collected by this site. 

We reserve the right to disclose your personal information as required by law and when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights and/or comply with judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process served on our website. 

If Coastal is involved in a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, you will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our website, of any change in ownership, uses of your personal information, and choices you may have regarding your personal information. We may also disclose your personal information to any other third party with your prior consent.

We also use other third parties such as a shipping company to fulfill orders, a credit card processing company to bill you for goods and services, provide customer service, and an email service provider to send out emails on our behalf. When you purchase items from us, we will share your PII with the third party, as necessary for the third party to provide that service. 

We, Coastal, and our [marketing partners], affiliates, or analytics or service providers, use technologies such as cookies, beacons, tags, and scripts, to analyze trends, administer the website, tracking users' movements around the website, and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. We may receive reports based on the use of these technologies by these companies on an individual and aggregated basis.

Our third party advertising partner employs a software technology called clear gifs (a.k.a. Web Beacons/Web Bugs), that help us better manage content on our site by informing us what content is effective. These track the online movement of Web users. Instead of being stored on the user's hard drive, clear gifs are embedded invisibly on Web pages and are about the size of the period.

Our third party advertising partner employs a software technology called clear gifs (a.k.a. Web Beacons/Web Bugs), that help us better manage content on our site by informing us what content is effective. These track the online movement of Web users. Instead of being stored on the user's hard drive, clear gifs are embedded invisibly on Web pages and are about the size of the period. 

Atlas and Akamai may use information about your visits to this and other websites in order to provide ads about goods and services of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by the third party, [click here for Atlas](http://www.atlassolutions.com/privacy.aspx) or [click here for Akamai](http://www.networkadvertising.org/). 

By providing your email address in conjunction with a purchase transaction you authorize Coastal to communicate with you by email regarding this purchase transaction. This authorization applies regardless of whether the purchase transaction is finalized. 

By using our services, you consent to our collection, use and disclosure of your personal information as follows:

  1. Our Privacy Compliance Officer, Sunny Dhillon, is accountable for our compliance with this privacy policy. If you have any questions, concerns or complaints about our privacy policy, please contact us in writing at the below:

Sunny Dhillon, Privacy Compliance Officer  
Coastal  
400-2955 Virtual Way  
Vancouver, BC V5M 4X6 

Or send an email to [privacy@coastal.com](mailto:privacy@coastal.com)

If your personal information changes, or if you no longer desire our service, you may correct, delete inaccuracies, or update it by updating your account information online, emailing our Vision Ambassadors at [visioncare@coastal.com](mailto:visioncare@coastal.com). Or by contacting us by telephone or postal mail at the contact information listed above. We will respond to your access request within 30 days.

We allow you to store your credit card information on the site so that it is easier for you to refill your prescriptions. This information is stored in an encrypted area of the site and may be removed at any time. We do not use this information for any other purpose. 

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. If you wish to cancel your account or request that we no longer use your information to provide you services contact us at the email address listed above. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements. 

  2. We use cookies for [our shopping cart, to remember users' settings (e.g. language preference), for authentication]. Users can control the use of cookies at the individual browser level. If you reject cookies, you may still use our website, but your ability to use some features or areas of our website may be limited.

We partner with a third party to either display advertising on our website or to manage our advertising on other sites. Our third party partner may use technologies such as cookies to gather information about your activities on this website and other sites in order to provide you advertising based upon your browsing activities and interests. If you wish to not have this information used for the purpose of serving you interest-based ads, you may opt-out by clicking here or here. Please note this does not opt you out of being served ads. You will continue to receive generic ads.

We use Local Storage, such as HTML5, to store content information and preferences. Third parties with whom we partner to provide certain features on our website or to display advertising based upon your web browsing activity also use Flash cookies and HTML5 to collect and store information. Various browsers may offer their own management tools for removing HTML5. To manage Flash cookies, please [click here.](http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager07.html)

We use pixels, or transparent GIF files, to establish which of our online adverts successfully bring people to our Site or the sites of our affiliates. The GIF files are provided by third parties who provide us with online advertising analysis. This system places a cookie on your browser when you enter our Site. Cookies are used to save information such as items you have placed in the cart, or previous items you have looked at. The information collected on our behalf, is anonymous and does not personally identify you. The information does not contain your name, address, telephone number or your e-mail address. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies but you can change your browser to reject them. Even without a cookie you can still use our Site. If you would like to know how to opt-out of the technologies mentioned above, please click here. 

We use third party advertising companies to serve ads on our behalf across the Internet. These third-party advertising companies employ cookie and Web Beacon (also referred to as 1x1 pixel.gifs or action tags) technology to measure and improve the effectiveness of ads for their clients. A cookie is a small text file that is stored on a user's computer for record-keeping purposes. To do so, these companies may use anonymous information about your visits to our website and other websites. This information can include: date/time of banner shown, their cookie, and the first three octets of the IP address. They do not collect personal information (PII) and are prohibited from using your personal identifying information for promotional purposes. This anonymous information can also be used for online preference marketing purposes. The use of cookies by third parties is not covered by our privacy statement. We do not have access or control over these cookies. These third parties use session ID cookies to make it easier for you to navigate our site. 

  3. We use pixels, or transparent GIF files, to establish which of our online adverts successfully bring people to our Site or the sites of our affiliates. The GIF files are provided by third parties who provide us with online advertising analysis. This system places a cookie on your browser when you enter our Site. Cookies are used to save information such as items you have placed in the cart, or previous items you have looked at. The information collected on our behalf, is anonymous and does not personally identify you. The information does not contain your name, address, telephone number or your e-mail address. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies but you can change your browser to reject them. Even without a cookie you can still use our Site. If you would like to know how to opt-out of the technologies mentioned above, please visit:  
[www.doubleclick.com/us/about_doubleclick/privacy/opting_out.asp](http://www.doubleclick.com/us/about_doubleclick/privacy/opting_out.asp)

We use third party advertising companies to serve ads on our behalf across the Internet. These third-party advertising companies employ cookie and Web Beacon (also referred to as 1x1 pixel.gifs or action tags) technology to measure and improve the effectiveness of ads for their clients. A cookie is a small text file that is stored on a user's computer for record-keeping purposes. To do so, these companies may use anonymous information about your visits to our website and other websites. This information can include: date/time of banner shown, their cookie, and the first three octets of the IP address. They do not collect personal information (PII) and are prohibited from using your personal identifying information for promotional purposes. This anonymous information can also be used for online preference marketing purposes. The use of cookies by third parties is not covered by our privacy statement. We do not have access or control over these cookies. These third parties use session ID cookies to make it easier for you to navigate our site. 

  4. We use third-party vendors, including Google, to show our ads on sites on the internet and to use cookies to serve ads based on your prior visits to our website. We use analytics data to inform and optimize our ad campaigns based on your prior visits to our website. You may opt out of Googles use of cookies by visiting the [Google Advertising Opt-Out Page](http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/ads/). More information on opting out of a third party vendors use of cookies is available by visiting the [Network Advertising Initiative Opt Out Page](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp). You may also opt out of our use of Google Analytics by visiting the [Google Analytics Opt-Out Page](http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout). We may have reporting of your aggregate interactions with our ads across the Google Display Network or DoubleClick for Advertisers in conjunction with activity on our website.

  5. Our site offers publicly accessible blogs or community forums. You should be aware that any information you provide in these areas may be read, collected and used by others who access them. Also if you use the customer review feature on our website which may contain personally identifiable information. We do obtain the customer's consent via email prior to posting the review to post their name along with their review. To request removal of your personal information from our blog, community forum, or testimonials contact us at [privacy@coastal.com](mailto:privacy@coastal.com). In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why. 

Atlas may use information about your visits to this and other websites in order to provide ads about goods and services of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by the third party, [click here](http://www.atlassolutions.com/privacy.aspx). 

### Security Policy

We take the security of your information very seriously. Our e commerce system uses the latest SSL (Secure Sockets Layer) technology - the industry standard for encryption technology. It is used to create a secure transaction environment for commerce on the Internet. If your browser and local network support the use of encrypted data transmissions, our Secure Checkout mode locks all information (i.e.: your credit card number) passed from you to Coastal in an encrypted envelope, making it extremely difficult to be intercepted by an unauthorized party. SSL technology is compatible with Netscape, Internet Explorer, AOL, Web TV and most other browsers. It is the same level of encryption technology that NASA and the CIA use. This ensures that your credit card information remains totally secure. It's about as secure as using your local bank machine. 

### Service-related Announcements

We will send you strictly service-related announcements on rare occasions when it is necessary to do so. For instance, if our service is temporarily suspended for maintenance, we might send you an email. 

Generally, you may not opt-out of these communications, which are not promotional in nature. If you do not wish to receive them, you have the option to deactivate your account. 

### Newsletters

If you wish to subscribe to our newsletter(s), we will use your name and email address to send the newsletter to you. Out of respect for your privacy, we provide you a way to unsubscribe. Please see the "Choice and Opt-out" section. 

### Opt-Out

We provide you the opportunity to "opt-out" of having your personal information used for certain purposes, when we ask for this information. For example, if you purchase a product/service but do not wish to receive any special offer emails from us, you may opt-out at anytime by following the unsubscribe link located at the bottom of each email communication. 

If you no longer wish to receive our newsletter and promotional communications, you may opt-out of receiving them by following the instructions included in each newsletter. 

We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore, while we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee its absolute security. 

If you have any questions about security on our Web site, you can email us at [privacy@coastal.com](mailto:privacy@coastal.com). 

### TRUSTe Licensee

The TRUSTe certification applies to the following properties:

In order to view our relationship with TRUSTe please visit the validation page visible by clicking on the TRUSTe seal. If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact TRUSTe at by [clicking here](https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request).

Effective Date: 03/16/2106

COPYRIGHT NOTICE. Copyright © Essilor Group Canada Inc., All rights reserved. Any rights not expressly granted herein are hereby reserved.
